字幕{教整理：眉如黛・W如
碜裕骇ovie・1895百年光影 QQ群
午餐半小时休息。
Half-hour dinner break.
受伤70个，失踪34个。
70 wounded and 34 were missing.
不好意思，我们的鸡肉沙拉已经卖完了。
I'm sorry. We're out of chicken salad.
南部边界的半里.把越南分成南北2部分...
Half mile south of the southern boundary
that separates North and South Vietnam.
在越南的过去一周里...
In this last week in Vietnam...
...据报道已有141个美国人死亡...
...there are a reported 141 American dead...
...391个重伤,还有47个被列为失踪.
...391 wounded, and 47 listed as missing.
别的消息.今天下午在华盛顿,国会...
Other news. In Washington
this afternoon, the Congressional...
嘿,博雷斯!我就想要个这样的妞,兄弟.
Hey, Birdlace!
I want a girl just like this, man.
宝贝!
Babe!
后面!
Back here!
拿到后边来!
Bring it back here now!
该死的,博雷斯.
Damn you, Birdlace.
不,你别,扔过来给我.
No, you don't. Back here to me.
看起来跟一卡通人物似的.
It looks like a cartoon.
一边去,兄弟.王八蛋子过来了,十一点钟方向.
Stand by, men.
Asshole approaching, 11 o'clock.
贝尔津,姑娘们...
Berzin, ladies...
这位是非科特.他想见你们.
This here is Fector.
He wanted to meet you.
是啊.
Yeah.
你们好吗?
How you guys hanging?
那么,我们能帮你做啥,非科特?
So, what can we do for you, Fector?
多纳文说你们有在赞助一个小团队活动。
Donavin says you guys are sponsoring
a little get-together.
我也想加入，如果可以的话。
I want in, if it's okay.
我不知道，非科特。我们是一个相当诺耐哦印
I don't know, Fector.
We're a pretty elite group.
-你说呢，博雷斯？-你知道规则么?
- What do you think, Birdlace?
- You know the rules?
你要是违反规定，你就别想要回你的投资了，一分钱都不可能，你明白不？
You break the rules, you don't get your jing
back, not a fucking dime. You got that?
你来参加这个活动带了人没，肥-科特？
Do you have anyone to bring
to this event, Fec-dork?
那是当然，我有带人。
Fucking A, I got someone to bring.
听起来挺诺穆铮兄弟们。你认为呢，本杰明？
Sounds pretty elite to me, guys.
What do you think, Benjamin?
非科特，你有50块吗？
Fector, you got the $50?
日，依我来看丫就像个杰出的候选人。
Shit. Looks like
an outstanding candidate to me.
太他妈帕恕
Out-fucking-standing.
如何啊，非科特，奥基喜欢你。
How about that, Fector? Okie likes you.
事实上，我们都喜欢你，那就意味着允许你加入。
In fact, we all like you.
That means you're in.
庆祝活动就在7点开始。
Festivities begin precisely at 19:00.
到时候你就去那。
You'll be there.
我会穿着蓝衣服，网球鞋和一条她妈的毛皮内衬护身三角绷带到那的。
I'll be there in dress blues, tennis shoes,
and a fur-lined fucking jockstrap.
走着瞧吧。
Count on it.
非科特？在我听起来更像是肥科特。
Fector? Sounds more like '"fective'" to me.
有病。
Defective.
那傻了吧唧的蠢蛋还在新兵训练营蹲着。
Dumb motherfucker
still shitting boot camp chow.
绝对的傻逼，明白咯。
Definitely. Roger that.
22个人了，这次可是最盛大的一次咯。
Twenty-two. That's the biggest ever.
我们要好好爽一把咯。
We going to have us a time.
是，长官，我们要好好爽一把。
Yes, sir, we going to have
some kind of time.
请注意，乘客们。
Attention, passengers.
去圣克鲁兹的班车已经被取消。
The bus to Santa Cruz has been canceled.
去洛杉矶的班车将会延迟20分钟。
The bus from Los Angeles
will be 20 minutes late.
好，兄弟们，站队。
All right, men. Fall in.
注意了！
Attention!
一个问题，兄弟们。
One question, men.
-我们是混蛋还是海军陆战队？-长官，我们是混蛋，长官！
- Are we assholes or Marines?
- Sir, assholes, sir!
-错！我们是海军陆战队！我们是什么？-长官，海军陆战队，长官！
- Wrong! We're Marines! What are we?
- Sir, Marines, sir!
而且我们不只是海军陆战队的。
And we are not just Marines.
我们是四蜂组合。我们是什么？
We are the Four Bees. What are we?
长官，我们是她妈的四蜂组合，对，对，长官！
Sir, the Four fucking Bees. Aye, aye, sir!
四蜂自合有一项特殊的任务。什么任务？
The Four Bees have a special mission.
What's that mission?
抓捕任何囚犯并且不变成其中一员！
To take no prisoners and not become one!
真他妈的好，兄弟们。
Out-fucking-standing, men.
7点钟集合。
Muster at 1900.
好好打猎，先生们。
Good hunting, gentlemen.
解散。
Fall out.
-打扰了，嗨。-嗨。
- Excuse me. Hi.
- Hi.
可能是个年纪更大的姐姐？
An older sister maybe?
麦吉。多比气死了，你现在这是个大麻烦。不好意思。
Maggie. Debbie's really mad at you.
You're in big trouble this time. Excuse me.
不好意思。我才刚到这。
Excuse me. I'm new in town.
我认为也许我们可以一起去观个光什么的。
I thought maybe we could see some sights.
看看金门大桥...
The Golden Gate...
你个死贱人.
You slut.
不好意思.我听到你说的了.
Excuse me. I overheard you.
我也是刚到这里.我有一张地图.
I'm new here, too. I've got a map.
你想去哪?
Where do you want to go?
哎呀,谢谢,不过...
Gee, thanks, but...
不不太感兴趣.我的意思是,不,我不需要你的帮助.
I'm not interested.
I mean, no, I don't need your help.
我得走了.
I got to go.
-他在哪?-你在跟我说话?
- Where is he?
- You talking to me?
是的,女士,现在告诉我,他在哪?
Yes, ma'am, now, where is he?
-谁?-你的丈夫.
- Who?
- Your husband.
我没有丈夫.
I don't have a husband.
-你没有丈夫?-没有.
- You don't have a husband?
- No.
那你男朋友呢?
Where's your boyfriend?
没有男朋友.你想干嘛?
No boyfriend. What is it you want?
你是女同性恋吗?
Are you a lesbian?
不,我不是.
No, I'm not.
一个像你这样的漂亮的小东西,没有老公,没有男友...
A pretty little thing like yourself
with no husband, no boyfriend...
你绝对是个同性恋.
You got to be a lesbian.
不,我只是自己一个人坐在这.就这样.
No, I'm just here by myself, that's all.
不再是独自一人咯,我的名字叫比尔.
,Not anymore. My name's Buell.
很多人叫我奥基.
A lot of people call me Okie.
你可以叫我奥基.
You can call me Okie.
要是你想的话.
Only if you wanted to.
贝蒂,嗨!
Betty, hi!
嘿,我不认识你.
Hey, I don't know you.
你什么意思啊你不认识我?
What do you mean you don't know me?
我们已经通了7个月的信了.
We've been writing to each other
for seven months.
我没说过我会来这跟你见面吗?
I said I'd meet you here?
贝蒂,是我啊,山姆,山姆本杰明.
Betty, it's me Sam, Sam Benjamin.
我不是贝蒂.我是鲁斯两只熊.
I'm not Betty. I'm Ruth Two Bears.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
你看起来就像是贝蒂啊...贝蒂林克斯莱格.
You look just like Betty... Betty Lynx Leg.
天啊,这...
Jesus, this...
天啊,这真是太尴尬了.
Jesus, this is really very embarrassing.
对不起,鲁斯.
I'm sorry, Ruth.
我得去喝一杯.
I need a drink.
让我请你喝杯酒吧.
Let me buy you a drink.
补偿你.
Make it up to you.
我发誓,我真的以为你就是贝蒂.
I swear, I thought you were Betty.
当我说起"随地吐痰的画面"...你确定你没有林克斯莱格的血统?
"When I say '"spitting image'"...
You have no Lynx Leg blood in you?
你好.
Hello.
海军陆战队已经着陆了.
The Marines have landed.
-噢,好极了.-我一个小时内就赶过去.
- Oh, great.
- I'll be there in an hour.
-我刚才说的是,格蕾迪斯...-是爱丽丝.
- What I was saying, Gladys...
- Alice.
对不起,爱丽丝.我是说你人很好.
Sorry, Alice. I was saying you're nice.
我是真诚的.
I'm being sincere.
听着,我是个美国海军.
Listen, I'm a United States Marine.
我明天就离开这前往冲绳岛了.
I'm leaving tomorrow morning to Okinawa.
我想在离开前拥有一个美好的时光,就这样.
I wanted to have a nice time, that's all.
-你想拥有一个美好的时光?-是啊.
- You want a nice time?
- Yeah.
去找个妓女吧。
Get yourself a streetwalker.
妈了个逼的！
Fucking shit!
不好意思。
Excuse me.
噢，雨下的真大啊。我们要被淋湿了。
Oh, it's pouring out.
We're going to get soaked.
你想来点什么？
What will you have?
一杯咖啡吧...
A cup of coffee's fine...
再给我来个看起来鲜美可口的甜甜圈谢谢.
And I'll take one of those delicious-looking
doughnuts, too, please.
-你想要哪种?-巧克力味的,谢谢.
- What kind you want?
- Chocolate, please.
呃,这些都是自家做的吗?
Say, are these things homemade?
不是.
No.
好吧,闻起来像是.
Well, they smell it.
我们很快就要关门了.
We're going to be closing soon.
哇哦.
Wow.
请别停下,你听起来很不错.
Please. Don't stop. You sound real good.
真的很棒.这是我最爱的歌之一.
It's great. It's one of my favorite songs.
实际上,让我想起...
Actually, it reminds me a lot of...
很多吉姆斯恩的歌.
,Of Jim Swaine's music.
你不这样认为吗?
Don't you think so?
我不认识他.
I don't know him.
哇哦.吉姆斯恩不认识?
Wow. Jim Swaine?
呃,他就是...
Well, he's just...
好吧,你总听说过迪伦吧?鲍勃迪伦?
Well, you've heard of Dylan, right?
Bob Dylan?
听说过.
Yeah.
吉姆斯恩对迪伦的音乐有很大的影响.
Jim Swaine is a major influence
on Dylan's music.
我还以为...
I thought...
...伍迪加斯里才是影响了迪伦的那个人.
...Woody Guthrie was Dylan's influence.
呃,也是啊.
Well, yeah.
先是伍迪,然后才是吉姆斯恩.
There's Woody,
and then there's Jim Swaine.
事实上,我觉得吉姆斯恩和合写了一些歌.
In fact, I think that Jim Swaine and Woody
cowrote some songs together.
如果我没记错的话.
If I'm not mistaken.
我以为伍迪自己创作了很多.
I thought Woody wrote pretty much
on his own.
有时候是的,他是写了很多,绝对的.
Sometimes he did. He did, most definitely.
不过有时候,他会,你知道的,和斯恩合作一下.
But sometimes, he would, you know,
collaborate with Swaine.
换句话来说,伍迪写歌词,斯恩来配曲.
In other words, Woody wrote the words,
and Swaine wrote the music.
其他时候,他们会换一下,知道我在说什么吗?
Other times, they'd switch.
See what I'm saying?
就像他的那首著名的歌曲.
Like that famous song of his.
你知道我说的是哪首吗?
You know the one I mean?
-这个岛屿属于你?-正是"这个岛屿属于你."
- This Land Is Your Land?
- This Land Is Your Land. Exactly.
噢,那个...
Yeah, that was...
那首是斯恩和加斯林的原创歌曲.
That was an original
by Swaine and Guthrie.
真奇怪.
That's strange.
我楼上有些乐谱,可是我不记得有看到过他的名字.
I've got the sheet music upstairs.
I don't remember seeing his name.
他曾是个代笔写手,有的时候.
He was a ghostwriter. Sometimes.
实际上,大多数时候.
In fact, most of the time.
萝斯,你休息时间结束了,把这些桌子收拾收拾.
Rose, your break's over.
Let's get those tables set up for tomorrow.
你的咖啡要凉掉了.
Your coffee's getting cold.
谢谢.
Thank you.
你自己也写歌么
?Do you write your own stuff?
啊天啊,不.
Jeez, no.
你应该写写.你有副好嗓子.
You should. You've got the voice for it.
-真的?-她妈的当然了.
- Really?
- Abso-fucking-lutely.
嘿,对不起.
Hey. My apologies.
我还不怎么懂得和女士相处.
I'm not used to being around ladies.
没关系.我得回去工作了.
It's okay. I should get back to work.
行.
Sure.
听着,我只是个愚蠢的锅盖头.
Listen, I'm just a dumb jarhead.
对不起.
I am sorry.
没关系.
It's okay.
那你们几点关门?
So what time do you close up here?
快了,再一会儿.
In a little while.
什么是锅盖头?
What's a jarhead?
那只是我们对自己的称呼.我是个美国海军陆战队员.
That's just what we call ourselves.
I'm a United States Marine.
我们这么说说是没事的,但是如果一个乌贼这么说,一个水手...
It's okay if we say it,
but if a squid says it, a sailor...
...那就要引起一场打斗了.
...then it's fist city.
不过要是女人这么说完全没问题,特别是一个能像你这样唱歌的.
It's all right if a woman says it,
especially if she sings like you.
谢谢.
Thanks.
非常感谢...
Thanks very much...
...锅盖头.
...jarhead.
-那么,你叫什么名字?-萝斯,萝斯范尼.
- So, what's your name?
- Rose, Rose Fenny.
萝斯咖啡馆.这是你开的店?
Rose's cafe. You own this place.
不,我妈妈的,她的名字也叫萝斯.
No. My mother does. Her name's Rose.
跟我一样,我外婆也是.
Same as me, same as my grandmother.
那很不错.
That's nice.
-你是个海军陆战队员?-是的,女士.
- You're a Marine?
- Yes, ma'am.
爱德华贝恩斯博雷斯?
Edward Baines Birdlace?
好吧,没那么好笑啦.
Okay. It's not that funny.
对不起,这名字还不错.
Sorry. It's a nice name.
谢了.
Thanks.
天啊,你看起来好凶悍.
Gosh, you look so angry.
我不是凶悍.我只是时刻准备着.
I'm not angry. I'm just ready.
为什么而准备?
Ready for what?
为一切.
Ready for anything.
生日:1944年11月26日.
Date of birth: November 26, 1944.
那很快就到了嘛.今天已经21号了.
That's soon. Today's the 21st.
在这星期一.19岁大生日.
This Monday. 19 big ones.
噢,生日快乐,博雷斯下士.
Well, happy birthday, Corporal Birdlace.
哎呀,谢谢.
Gee, thanks.
我最好赶紧撤了,得去个派对.
I better shove off soon. Going to a party.
生日派对?
Birthday party?
不,就是个...寻常的派对.
No, just... Sort of a regular party.
嘿,也许你愿意跟我一块去不.
Say, maybe you'd like to go with me.
实际上,我还在工作呢.
Actually, I'm still working.
行,好吧.我理解.
Sure. Right. I understand.
不,我得在这呆到今晚关门为止.
No. I've got to be here till closing tonight.
萝斯,听着.
Rose, listen.
我是个海军陆战队员,还困陆战队的都是混蛋,大家都知道这一点.
I'm a Marine and Marines are jerks.
Everybody knows that.
如果你不想跟我一块去,就直说好了.
If you don't want to go with me, just say so.
只是...我妈就得一个人了.
It's just... My mom would be alone.
呃,我也不想给任何人带来麻烦,那么...
Well, I don't want to get anyone in trouble
with their old lady, so...
很高兴认识你,萝斯.很高兴认识你.
It was nice to have met you, Rose.
Nice to have met you.
再见.
'Bye.
萝斯?
Rose?
你唱得真的很好.
You sing real good.
相当好.
Real good.
妈的.
Shit.
你快做完了吗,亲爱的?
You almost done, honey?
这是什么,星期三?不知道今晚电视上会放什么.
What is this, Wednesday?
I wonder what's on TV tonight.
我们下楼去看点好看的节目.
We'll go upstairs
and watch something nice.
-我有一些新的绿色邮票.-不好意思.
- I got some new green stamps...
- Excuse me.
我喜欢骄傲的女人...
I love women that take pride in...
-走开点.-埃迪!
- Go away.
- Eddie!
我和你一块去好吗?
I'm going with you, okay?
棒极了.
This is great.
太好了.
It's great.
-你妈怎么办?-没事的
- What about your mother?
- What about her?
好极了.
This is great.
我现在先去换下衣服.
I'm going to go get changed now.
-是什么样的派对?-普通派对.
- What kind of party is this?
- A party party.
一个化妆派对吗?-是的,化妆派对.
- A dress-up party?
- Yes, a dress-up party.
好的.
Okay.
听着,萝斯,要不把你的吉他也带上吧?
Listen, Rose, why don't you bring
your guitar along?
我还没准备好在一群人面前唱呢.
I'm not ready to sing in front
of an audience.
也行,你能去就已经很好了.
That's fine, too.
It'll be great just to have you along.
-萝斯?-我要去个派对,好吗?
- Rosie?
- I'm going to a party, okay?
-还有很多活呢.-我明天开张前会做的.
- There's still all this work.
- I'll do it before we open.
萝斯...
Rose...
我保证.
I promise.
老天啊.
Jesus God.
你看起来很漂亮.
You look great.
是吗?
Yeah?
棒极了。
Outstanding.
谢谢、
Thanks.
真高兴我最终决定去了。
I'm really glad I decided to come.
是啊，好极了，我也很高兴。
Oh, great. Me, too.
能暂时远离餐馆感觉真好。
It's nice to get away from the restaurant...
...远离我妈
...from my mom.
我并不是讨厌她什么的.只是她的一生都投入到那家餐馆里去了.
I don't hate her or anything.
It's just, her whole life's the restaurant.
而我不想也那样.
I don't want it to be like that.
这一点也不能怪你.
I don't blame you a bit.
咪咪的烦恼.
The Trouble with Mimi.
-你看过这个吗?-我不怎么去电影院.
- Did you see this?
- I don't go to flicks much.
这种片子能把我逼疯.
This kind of thing drives me crazy.
有些人在为了生存和自由而斗争...
There are people right now, fighting
for their lives and for their freedom...
...当我们在这里看那些毫无意义的垃圾的时候.
...while here we are watching this trash
which doesn't mean anything.
-那你为毛还看?-我妈呗.
- Then why did you see it?
- My mom.
她爱死这片子了.
She loved it.
我们最近经常意见不合.她很容易满足,你知道的,就这么过日子.
We don't agree on anything lately.
She's content, you know, living her life.
可我不想...
I don't want to...
我想对这个世界有所影响.
I want to have an effect on the world.
我想脱离这里,融入到其他环境中去.
I want to get out there and get involved.
你懂的,我想加入和平卫队...
You know, I'd like to join the Peace Corps...
...或者可能下到南部去帮助那里...
...or maybe go down south
and help out there...
我不知道.
I don't know.
这真是让人无奈.
It's just so frustrating.
恩,我理解你的意思.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
-真高兴我来了.-我也很高兴.
- I'm really glad I decided to come.
- Me, too.
能跟人聊天感觉真好.真的很好.
It's really nice to talk to someone.
It's really nice.
那是啊.
It is.
大型派对!
Big party!
萝斯,你的嘴唇长的很好看.
Rose, you got really nice lips.
什么?
What?
你嘴唇长的很好看.你涂口红了吗?
You got nice lips. Are you wearing lipstick?
是啊.-是吗?
- Yes.
- Yeah?
好像有点褪掉了,我看看.
It's kind of wearing down, I see.
-有吗?-有一点点,带唇膏了吗?
- It is?
- A little bit. Got more?
-我该补补吗?-当然.
- Should I put some more on?
- Sure.
好的.
Okay.
让我来试试.
Let me try.
-可以吗?-行啊.
- Can I, please?
- Okay.
埃迪...
Eddie...
别动.
Hold still.
埃迪...
Eddie...
你涂唇膏涂得跟我差不多好.
You put on lipstick about as good as I do.
你该把唇膏涂在嘴唇上.
You're supposed to put lipstick on the lips.
全涂到我的...
It's all over my...
现在全涂到我的嘴巴外边了.
It's all over my mouth now.
等下,也许我可以修整好.
Wait. Maybe I can fix this.
全涂出来了.
It's all over the place.
好了,现在好了,对吗?
There. That's fine, right?
算了，别管了。
Never mind. Forget about it.
你看起来不错的。
You look fine.
你觉得我看起来好吗？
You think I look okay?
很好的。
It's all right.
...夜光俱乐部...
'"The Nitelite.'"
哇哦.看起来像是个相当不错的地方,哈?
Wow. Looks like a pretty fancy place, huh?
萝斯,这个派对其实没什么意思,我们没必要非得进去...
Rose, this party's no big deal.
We don't have to go in...
我想去.
I'd like to. Yeah.
我们可以去别的地方的,如果你只是想跳舞.
We can go somewhere else
if you just want to dance.
没事的.
That's okay.
好吧,来吧.
All right, come on.
-拿去吧,伙计.-谢谢.
- There you go, buddy.
- Thanks.
你的朋友吗?
Friend of yours?
来吧.
Come on.
晚上好啊,博雷斯下士.晚上好,女士.
Good evening, Corporal Birdlace.
Good evening, ma'am.
你找了个不错的女伴嘛,下士.
Fine woman you got there, Corporal.
我确定会把这个加到给检察长的报告里的.
I'll be sure to include this in my report
to the inspector general.
-谢谢,长官.-好运,下士.
- Thank you, sir.
- Good luck, Corporal.
等下.
Wait a second.
-我只是想....-你看起来很棒.
- I just want to...
- You look great.
-真的吗?真的,
- Really?
- Really. You do.
-好吧.-让我们进去吧.
- Okay.
- Let's hit it.
你想要一个派对,这就给你个派对.
You want a party? You got yourself a party.
-嘿,博雷斯!-嘿,扎沃斯基!
- Hey, Birdlace!
- Hey, Zaworsky!
这位是萝斯.
This is Rose.
-嗨，萝斯。-嗨，萝斯。
- Hi, Rose.
欢迎来到天堂，下士。
Welcome to paradise, Corporal.
谢谢，下士。
Thank you, Corporal.
-致四蜂组合！-还有他们的女士们。
- To the Four Bees!
- And their ladies.
还有他们的姑娘们。
And their girls.
-永远忠诚。-永远忠诚！
- Semper fi.
- Semper fi!
这里只有三个B啊，贝尔津，本杰明，博雷斯。
That's only three B's.
Berzin, Benjamin, and Birdlace.
我的名字叫比尔。他们只是叫我奥基而已。
My name's Buell. They just call me Okie.
你们都是在新兵训练营里成为朋友的吗？
You've all been friends since boot camp?
不，在训练营里，都是按身高排列的。
No. In boot camp, you line up by height.
在步兵训练营里，在新兵训练营后的步兵训练，是按照字母排序的。
In ITR, infantry training after boot camp,
it's alphabetical order.
于是我们都被排在一起了。
So we always lined up together.
然后关系就非常好了。
Got to be pretty tight.
大家之后就开始叫我们四蜂组合。
Everyone started calling us the Four Bees.
然后我们从那以后就黏在一块了。
And we've stuck together since then.
那么说，你们排对排一起就得成为朋友了？
So, you got to be friends
from standing in line?
呃，很高兴见到你们，真的。
Well, I'm happy to meet you all. I really am.
他妈的我们的酒水呢？
Where's our fucking drinks?
-你们挺喜欢说粗口的嘛。-不，我们喜欢喝酒。
- You guys like to swear.
- No. We like to drink.
这不是什么大不了的，萝斯，只是单词而已。过了一会，你就习以为常了。
No big thing, Rose. It's just words.
After a while, you don't even hear it.
P都不算。
Don't mean shit.
-空点位置出来。-我已经喝了两瓶了。
- Make room for another round.
- I've already had two.
亲爱的，别担心。
Honey, don't worry about it.
这只是迈泰（加勒比香槟），酒精度数很低的。
It's just a mai tai. Very weak drink.
相信我，你不会喝醉的。
Trust me. You won't get drunk.
好吧，喝光吧，我再叫两瓶。
Right. Drink up. I'll take another double.
大家都进舞池来！
Everyone on the dance floor!
谢谢。
Thanks.
先生们，我说我们该跳舞了。
Gentlemen, I say we dance.
好的。
Right.
想跳支舞吗？两只熊小姐？
Care to dance, Miss Two Bears?
来吧，亲爱的，让我们动起来。
Come on, darling. Let's hit it.
让我们掀起一阵暴风雨吧。
Let's see if we can make a rainstorm.
让他们见识见识我们的厉害。
Let's show them what we got.
-你生我的气了吗？-没有。
- Are you mad at me?
- No.
-呃，你明显生气了。-我比一只双相的猫头鹰还开心。
- Well, you sure seem mad.
- I'm happier than a two-peckered owl.
就是那个该死的女服务生。
It's the fucking waitress.
来吧，埃迪，我们跳舞去吧。
Come on, Eddie. Let's dance.
我们马上就去，她要先把她的酒喝完。
We'll be there in a minute.
She has to finish her drink still.
来吧，甜心，挪动你的屁股跳舞吧。
Come on, honey.
Get off your ass and dance.
还有严格的比赛正在进行呢。
Got some tough competition out there.
-玩得开心吗？博雷斯？-啊，是啊，继续啊，混蛋。
- Having a good time, Corporal Birdlegs?
- Yeah, yeah. Carry on, asshole.
-博雷斯？-只是个外号。
- Birdlegs?
- It's just a nickname.
-服务生！-别再喝了。
- Waitress!
- Don't drink any more.
跟我说说话。
Talk to me.
这是哪个种类的鸟？
What kind of a bird is that?
一只知更鸟。快乐的知更鸟。
A bluebird, the bluebird of happiness.
看见没?它会飞。把我带离所有的烦恼...
See? It flies.
It carries me from all the troubles...
...把我带去充满欢乐的地方.
...and takes me to where it's all happy.
真是狗扯蛋的.
Crock of shit.
成真过吗?
Does it ever work?
我们离开这吧.
Let's get out of here.
我还以为我们要去跳舞的.
I thought we were supposed to dance.
你是个很好的姑娘,这地方烂透了.
You're a nice girl. This is a fucked-up place.
我想跳舞,来吧.
I'd like to dance. Come on.
让我们动起来,博雷斯.
Let's hit it, Birdlegs.
好吧,保持忠诚,要么做,要么死.
Yeah. Semper fi, do or die.
你给她几分?
What do you give her?
-4分.-4分.
- Four.
- Four?
她都不是个女的，看在上帝的份上。
She's not even a woman, for Christ's sake.
放屁。
Bullshit.
她是个她妈的异装癖。
She's a fucking guy in drag.
你怎么能给她4分？
How can you give her a four?
狗日的，还真是个男的。
Son of a bitch, that is a guy.
那我要给他7分、
I'll give him a seven.
-你玩的开心不？-是啊。
- You having a good time?
- Yes.
看看我们有什么好货？
What have we here?
噢，我的天啊。
Oh, my god.
真他妈狗日的。
That son of a bitch.
她很给力。
She's nice.
先生们，我想我们已经有个胜者了。
Gentlemen, I think we got a winner here.
贝尔津赢了，大贝尔津。
Berzin wins. Big Berzin.
胜者！
Winner!
-10分！10分。
- Ten.
-怎么了？-没什么。
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
老天。
Jesus.
-给那个几分？-荣誉奖吧。
- How many points for that?
- Honorable mention.
胜者来咯！
Here's the man!
奖金呢？
Where's the money?
不可思议。
Unbelievable.
不可思议啊，老兄，你他妈在哪找到她的？
Unbelievable, man.
Where the fuck did you find her?
那可是他妈的顶级机密。
That's top-fucking-secret.
恭喜你，你个烂人，老天啊，她简直丑成一逼了。
Congratulations, you piece of shit.
God, was she butt-ugly.
赢得当之无愧啊，连续四次稳赢!
A well-deserved win. That's four in a row.
她妈的整个陆战队还没人连着四次赢的.
Nobody in the entire fucking Marine Corps
ever won four in a row.
我得说我可是个幸运的家伙.
I'd say I'm one lucky motherfucker.
我也觉得你是个幸运的家伙.
I think you're one lucky motherfucker.
-别灰心啊,本杰明.-去你妈的.
- No hard feelings, Benjamin.
- Eat my ass.
也去你妈的.
Fuck you, too.
噢,天啊.
Oh, boy.
-才给50块? -饶了我吧.
-Only $50?
- Cut me some slack, will you?
饶了你?你在字典里找到这个词的?
Slack? You find '"slack'" in the dictionary.
在狗屎和梅毒之间.
Between '"shit'" and '"syphilis.'"
那打的费呢!我付了8块钱打的费诶.
Cab fare. I paid $8 for that cab.
贝尔津,我告诉你你可不是在和牧师谈话.
Berzin, this ain't the chaplain
you're talking to.
你来找我帮忙,我帮了,但是要五五分成,我们说好的.
You come to me for help. I help,
for half the money. That was the deal.
别她妈跟我说什么打的费.
Don't give me shit about a fucking cab.
我她妈才懒得鸟你,你个该死的婊子.麻痹给你就给你.
I'm not giving you shit, you goddamn slut.
Take your goddamn money.
你个草比的混蛋!老天啊...
You fucking asshole! God...
操他妈的锅盖头.你们全都是混蛋.
Fucking jarheads. You're all assholes.
怎么了,玛西?
What's wrong, Marcie?
那男的是个混蛋.
The man's an asshole. That's what's wrong.
他说,"嘿,牙龈妹,想不想赚50块...
He says, '"Hey, Gums, how'd you like
to make $50...
而且你不用跟任何人上床,我就说,那前提是什么?
'"...and you don't have to do nobody? '"
I say, '"What's the catch? '"
他说没前提.然后告诉我这个斗狗比赛.
'"No catch.'" So he tells me
about this dogfight thing.
于是我就说,行.
So I say, '"Sure.'"
我甚至连假牙都没戴.
I even offer not to wear my teeth.
不好意思,我不明白.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
要死,算了.
Shit. Never mind.
不,我想听听.
No. I'd like to hear.
其实也还好,不是么?
It's not really as bad as it sounds, all right?
免费鸡尾酒,免费啤酒...
Free cocktail, free beer...
...然后他们会很礼貌.
...and they got to be polite.
那些就是规矩.他们必需得礼貌.
Those are the rules. They got to be polite.
-什么规矩?-斗狗赛的规矩.
- What rules?
- The rules of the dogfight.
你看,他们每个人都压点钱,50块啊,70块或75块等等...
See, they each put in some money,
like $50, $70, $75...
谁?
Who does?
那些混蛋,陆战队员.
The assholes, the Marines.
然后此外他们还要租下这个这方,买吃的和喝的...
And out of that they rent the joint,
pay for the food and the booze...
...剩下的钱就作为奖金.
...and the rest of the money
goes to prize money.
最让我气愤的是他们还以为他们自己长得多好看.
The thing that gets me is how great
they think they look.
你有见过一帮这么傻逼的人么?
You ever seen such a pack of pukes?
还有奖金的?
There's prize money?
对,哪个男的带的女的最丑...
That's right.
The ugliest woman wins $100...
...就能赢得100块.
...for the guy who brings her.
我是最丑的,所以赢了.
I'm the ugliest, so I win.
但是,知道么...
Only, see...
...我也没那么丑.你应该看看我装扮过后的样子.
...I ain't really that ugly. You should
see me when I'm really dressed up.
噢，上帝啊，太糟糕了。
Oh, God. This is awful.
玛西，你肯定觉得很难过。
Marcie, you must feel terrible.
也没那么难过。
It's not so bad.
至少我赚了50块。
At least I got $50.
你除了呕吐啥都没得到。
All you got was sick.
嘿！
Hey!
-玩得如何啊，屎鸟？-很好。
- How you doing there, Shitbird?
- Good.
你刚赢了荣誉奖。
You just won honorable mention.
有26块奖金可拿。
That's $26 in prize money.
幸好她吐了，否则我们就要给非科特了。
It's a good thing she puked up
or we'd have to give it to Fector.
可比一把刺刀顶着你屁股好多了。
Hell of a lot better than a bayonet
up your ass.
向来都是。
Always.
喂！
Hey!
你少装正经。
Don't you dare '"hey'" me.
你就是个残忍的，没良心的，无知的怪胎。
You are a cruel, heartless, ignorant creep.
要是我是个男人，我非把你扁成肉酱不可。
If I were a man, I'd beat you to a pulp.
谁给你的权利去这么对待别人？
Who gave you the right
to treat people like this?
这简直恶毒！
It's vicious!
你们都是恶毒的人！
All of you are just vicious!
对不起！
I'm sorry!
你还对不起？你根本没有感情。
How can you be sorry?
You have no feelings.
你只是个毫无价值的人渣。
You're just a worthless excuse
for a human being.
-喂，他是我的船友诶！-闭嘴，你个变态！
- Hey, that's my shipmate!
- Shut up, you creep!
你的道歉对我来说什么都不是。
Your apology means nothing to me.
每个从你嘴巴里吐出来的字都是腐烂的肮脏的谎言。
Everything out of your mouth
has been rotten, dirty lies.
我真后悔碰到你。
I'm sorry I ever met you.
好吧。
Okay.
天啊，真是个贱人。
God, what a bitch.
你在哪找到她的？
Where did you find her?
混球！
Jerk!
看在上帝的份上。
For Christ's sakes.
这都搞什么呀？
What the hell was that about?
老天！你们得好好控制你的女人。
Jesus Christ!
You should be able to control your woman.
萝斯。
Rose.
恩？
What?
现在才八点半，什么派对啊，那么早结束的？
It's 8:30. What kind of party ends so early?
我想早点回家来。
I decided to come home early.
你玩得开心不？
You have a good time?
是啊，还不错，我去练吉他了，
Yeah. It was nice.
I'm going to go practice my guitar.
别太响，好吗？
Not too loud, okay?
Repent!
喂，走路看着点。
Hey, watch your step.
Repent!
滚开。
Get the fuck out of here with that bullshit.
成人动画！
Cartoons for adults!
我爱胜利的感觉，下士！感觉真他妈好。
I love winning, Corporal!
It feels so fucking good.
来，我给你拿了瓶啤酒。
Here. I got you a beer.
别他妈老盯着我。
Quit eye-fucking me.
上帝！
Jesus!
这玩意儿还他妈要计时的。
They got these fucking things timed.
先是她刚要脱奶罩的时候就停。
First it stops just when
she takes off her bra.
现在又在她要脱内裤的时候停。
Now it stops just as she
takes off her panties.
气死老子了。
That pisses me off.
来，我们戴上帽子。
Let's put on our hat.
用肚子顶着那皮套。
Belly up to that holster.
你看起来就像老爸的牛仔小姑娘。
You look like Daddy's little cowgirl.
现在，要记住最重要的是....
Now, what's the most important thing
to remember...
...在一场野蛮的西部枪战中.
...during a Wild West shootout?
杀,杀,杀.
Kill, kill, kill.
很好,找到适当的位置.列好队.
Right. Get in position.
Line that son of a bitch up.
-开始！-杀！杀！杀！
- Draw!
- Kill! Kill! Kill!
你在干什么？打扰一下，女士，我得跟他说两句。
What are you doing?
Excuse me, ma'am. I got to talk to him.
-怎么了？-斗狗赛结束了。
- What's going on?
- The dogfight's over.
好啊，现在慢慢脱下短裤。
Okay, now half-mast those skivvies.
贱人！操你大爷的机器！
Bitch! Fucking machine!
干嘛，你才刚学会走路？
What, you just learn to walk?
奥基，再给我个硬币。
Okie, give me another nickel.
-可以，但是我也要看。-好啊。
- All right, but I get to see, too.
- Okay.
-我是说真的。-我也是说真的，给我。
- I'm serious.
- I'm serious. Give it to me.
博雷斯去哪了？
Where did Birdlace go?
他闪人了，说会去Navy Bill's跟我们会合。
He took off,he said he'd meet us at Navy Bill's.
要是我再看不到她的屁股，我就要来干你了。
If I don't see her ass soon,
I'm going to hump you.
有狗！
Dog!
萝斯，怎么回事？谁在外面？
Rosie, what is it? Who's out there?
没什么，就船长（狗名）在叫呢。
It's all right. It's just Captain.
过来。
Here.
来呀。
Come on.
来呀，到这来。
Come on. Here.
乖孩子，你个了不起的狗崽子。
Good boy. Yeah.
You're a big fucker, aren't you?
哦？还想要？看看你那对耳朵。
Yeah? Want some? Look at those ears.
好了，淡定。
Okay, easy.
狗娘养的！
Motherfucker!
你想干嘛？
What do you want?
挺漂亮的花么。
Pretty hokey, isn't it?
对不起，我觉得你会喜欢。
Sorry. I thought you'd like it.
我有赢得什么吗？
Did I win anything?
什么都没。
Nothing.
你还不够资格。
You were disqualified.
-骗人。-萝斯，我发誓。
- Liar.
- Rose, I swear.
那别的姑娘呢？
What about those other girls?
她们怎么？
What about them?
她们的感受呢？你真的以为她们没感受吗？
What about their feelings? Do you honestly
think they have no feelings?
她们对此一无所知，再说，你不一样。
They didn't know anything about it.
Besides, you're different.
我参加过6次斗狗。
I've been to six different dogfights.
你是第一个姑娘我尝试着劝她别去的。
You're the first girl I ever tried to talk
out of going.
-才没有。-真的，你不记得了吗？
- You did not.
- Yes, ma'am. You don't remember?
在夜光俱乐部门前，我试着阻止过你。
In front of the Nitelite? I tried to stop you.
还有跳舞前也阻止过。当你跳舞的时候，就是最终裁决。
And before dancing, too.
When you dance, that's final judging.
真是疯狂，我真不理解你，
That's crazy. I don't understand you.
有很多操蛋的东西我也不明白。
There's a lot of shit I don't understand.
我从来都不道歉的。
I don't apologize, ever.
但是我却大老远跑回来跟你道歉，
And I came all the fuck way back here
to apologize.
我真的也不明白。
And I don't understand that.
我想带你去吃晚饭...
I wanted to take you out to dinner...
...尽量补偿你,要是可能话...
...and try to make things up to you
if possible...
...现在我站在这里感觉就像个他妈的白痴.
...and I'm standing here now
feeling like an idiot.
所以,管他妈的.
So, fuck it.
如果你不想我在这,如果你真的很讨厌我...
If you don't want me around
and I'm a pain in your ass...
...尽管叫我离开,我马上就走.
...just tell me to leave, and I'm gone.
我想你停止说脏话.
I want you to stop swearing.
可以.
Okay.
那好吧.
-什么那好吧?-那好吧,我们去吃晚饭.
- Okay what?
- Okay, let's go to dinner.
但是如果这也是你们斗狗赛的一部分,我就杀了你.
But if this is part of your dogfight,
I'll kill you.
不,萝斯,这不是.
No, Rose, it's not.
我保证.这只是你和我一块去一个不错的地方吃顿不错的饭.
I promise. It's just you and I
at a nice joint having a nice dinner.
我们甚至都不会再提起这个斗狗赛.
We won't ever mention this dogfight again.
遵命.
Roger that.
这将只是一个寻常的约会,就两个普通人进行一个普通的约会.
It'll just be like a regular date,
just two regular people on a regular date.
对.
Right.
你知道博雷斯这人的,他可能现在就在外面行动呢.
Well, knowing Birdlace,
he's probably out looking for action.
说到行动...
Speaking of action...
你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
两个美女居然给一群甲板猿泡了!
Two beautiful women lost
to a detachment of deck apes!
-哟,我还以为我闻到乌贼屎了呢.-我也闻到了.
- Well, I thought I smelled squid shit.
- I smell it.
你们是不是想吃我的屎?
How'd you like to eat my shit?
操你妈的锅盖头.
Fucking jarhead.
打!打!
Fight! Fight!
Market and Powell站到了.
-我们在这下车?-对.
- Do we get off here?
- Yeah.
我知道一处地方.
I think I know a place.
这里.
Here.
我们还能找家更好的.
We can do better.
-埃迪,这个餐馆不错啊.-我们还能找家更好的.
- Eddie, this is a nice restaurant.
- We can do better.
-你好,需要什么帮助吗?-恩,打扰一下,两人餐.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah. Excuse me. Dinner for two.
-您有预约吗?-恩,我的秘书打来过,叫基尔默.
- Do you have a reservation?
- Yes, my secretary called in. Gilmore.
那个也不重要啊,那里不是还有很多位置嘛.
Not that that should matter,
being there's plenty of room.
是的,可是除非你穿一件夹克衫...
Yes, sir, there is,
but unless you have a jacket...
...否则我就无法让您入座.
...I can't seat you.
我就穿着夹克啊.
I'm wearing a jacket.
您穿的是件风衣,先生.
You're wearing a windbreaker, sir.
我指的是正式用餐穿的夹克,或者至少要一条领带或与运动外套.
I was speaking of a dinner jacket
or at least a tie and sports coat.
你就不能让我们坐在后面吗,远离通道?
Couldn't you just put us in the back,
out of the way?
这是我在美国的最后一个晚上了...
It's my last night stateside...
...我想带我女朋友吃顿晚餐.
...and I wanted to take my girl
out to dinner.
对不起,先生,我们这里有严格的条例.
I'm sorry, sir,
but it's a rule strictly enforced.
好吧,谢谢.
Well, thank you.
-那男的是个混球!-他只是在做他的工作而已.
- That man's a prick!
- He was doing his job.
放屁!就像个二级中尉,给他们点权利...
Bullshit! Just like a 2nd lieutenant,
give them some power...
...他们就跟狗吃屎一样都涌过来.
...they roll in it like dogs in shit.
让他们感觉像变成了狼一样,实际上还不是一只狗.
Makes them feel like wolves
instead of the little lap dog that he is.
我非整死他.
I'm going to burn his ass.
埃迪,怎么回事啊?
Eddie, what is the problem?
我们应该好好吃顿饭,开开心心约会的.
We were supposed to have
a nice, normal date.
没什么,我只是肩负任务而已.
There's no problem.
Just a man with a mission.
什么任务?
What kind of mission?
你和我一起对抗混球.
You and me against the pricks.
听懂了吗?
Are you with me?
今晚简直太疯狂了.
It has just been the craziest night.
埃迪的祖父去世了,我们得赶着去做午夜弥撒.
ddie's grandfather dies,
and we're headed for midnight mass.
把那件放回去.
Put that back where it belongs.
埃迪的衣柜里没有适合的参加葬礼的衣服.
Eddie just doesn't have appropriate
funeral wear hanging in his closet.
我理解.可是现在都那么晚了,我们刚还在睡觉呢.
I understand. But it's late. We were asleep.
我知道,我很抱歉,只是...
I know, I'm very sorry, it's just...
我们只要一件夹克就行了,这样埃迪能以最好的姿态前往.
We'd just like one jacket
so Eddie can look his best.
-亲爱的,快点.-好的,亲爱的.
- Please, darling, hurry.
- Okay, darling.
我尽快.
I'm hurrying as fast as possible.
埃迪选不好了,他有点震惊.
Eddie's having trouble making decisions.
He's shook up.
怎么回事啊?
What the hell's going on?
他们要去参加一个葬礼.
They're going to a funeral.
萝斯,你刚才的那些胡扯简直棒极了.让我印象深刻啊.
Rose, that was outstanding bullshit.
I was really impressed.
你在那乱扔衣服还真不容易.
It wasn't easy with you
throwing jackets all over.
晚上好,双人晚餐.
Good evening. Dinner for two, please.
谢谢.
Thanks.
看啊.真好真干净啊!
Look. It's so nice, so clean!
萝斯,你觉得坐这里怎样?
Rose, what do you think of this one?
嘿,朋友,这边,这边正好,谢谢.
Hey, friendly. Over here.
This will be just fine, thanks.
请坐.
Please.
这是我的荣幸.
It's my pleasure.
非常感谢.
Thank you so much.
你太好了,这是给你的小费,一块钱.
You've been so wonderful.
This is for you. $1.
-不必要吧.-我坚持请您收下.
- That won't be necessary.
- Please, I insist!
你就值一块钱.不是吗?
You're worth $1. Isn't he?
看见没?你就是值一块钱.
See? You are worth $1.
谢谢你的一切时间和努力.
Thank you so much for your time and effort.
等着吧我跟他还没完呢,他不会知道还有什么好戏要上演.
Just wait till I'm through with him.
He won't know whether to shit or go blind.
你已经开心了啊,为什么还要这么做.
You've had your fun.
Why do you have to do this?
别人打我一拳,我还他十拳.
Someone dumps on me five pounds,
I dump back fifty.
我跟那个混球还没完.
I'm not through with that jack-off, yet.
要是你要浪费今天一晚上让他不好过...
If you spend the night
making him miserable...
...那我就回家了.
...I am going home.
-啥?-我是说真的.
- What?
- I'm serious.
你在说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
我们来这是想好好吃顿饭的,我必须从他地方得到点尊重.
We came here to have a nice dinner.
And I'd like some respect from him.
你也应该得到点尊重.
You deserve respect, too.
而且我们也像别人一样是付了钱的.
We're paying just like everyone else.
你就靠这个来获取尊重?
That's how you get respect?
人都他妈的那么白痴.
People are such goddamn idiots.
我知道他么是.
I know they are.
可是为什么要花费你所有的力气去跟每个人较劲呢?
But what's the point of spending all your
energy trying to get even with everybody?
因为这感觉很好.这感觉他妈的好极了,特别是...
Because it feels great.
It feels fucking great, especially...
而且为什么每个从你嘴巴里说出来的字都是脏话?
And what's the point of every word
out of your mouth being a curse word?
你们准备好点菜了吗?
Are you ready to order now?
是的,该死的.
Yes, goddamn it.
我要来一份他妈的水煮鱼...
I'm going to have
the fucking poached salmon...
...配上狗娘养的米饭...
...with the son-of-a-bitching rice...
...再来一份操大爷的沙拉...
...and a dirty-bastard salad...
...配上屎一般的羊乳干酪酱.
...with a shitload of Roquefort dressing.
谢谢.
Thank you.
还有不知道这位混蛋想吃什么.
And who knows what this asshole wants.
我就来瓶狗日的啤酒好了.
I'll just take a fucking beer.
谢谢.
Thank you.
-你就点一瓶啤酒?-是啊.
- That's all you're going to have, a beer?
- Yeah.
你肯定饿坏了.
You must be starved.
没,我不饿.
No, I'm not starved.
-这是您点的菜.-谢谢.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
我就把它放在这里.
I'll just put this over here for now.
水煮鱼和抓饭.
Poached salmon and rice pilaf.
看起来真美味啊.你觉得呢?
It's beautiful. Isn't this beautiful?
是啊,看起来很好吃,相当好吃.
Yeah. That looks good, real good.
看吧,你的确饿了.
See, you are hungry.
你为什么不点些东西呢?
Why didn't you order anything?
我付不起.
I couldn't pay for it.
我是说我能付得起那个，和这瓶酒，不过到发薪日钱只能付得起这些。
I mean I can pay for that, and for this,
but that's all till payday.
你这是干什么？
What's that for?
你干嘛？
What are you doing?
谢了。
Thanks.
我去结账。
I'm going to hit the head.
好的，我在外面等你。
Okay I'll wait outside.
我知道他刚才对你很无礼。
I know that he was so rude to you.
但是我觉得靠外表和穿着...
But I don't think it's fair
to prejudge people...
...去预先判断别人是不公平的.
...on how they look or how they're dressed.
你觉得呢?
Don't you think?
谢谢你.
Thank you.
你在笑嘻嘻的在笑什么?
So, what are you grinning about?
我在想你头发长一点,少了脸上那块淤青...I was wondering what you'd look like
with your hair a little longer, and without...
...会是怎么样.
...that bruise on your face.
呃,不会好看很多,那是肯定的.
Well, not much better. That's for sure.
我们有句话是这么说的:
We've got a saying:
...比上不足,比下有余...那说的就是我.
'"Shot at and missed. Shit at and hit.'"
That's me.
那么,很快我就该送你回家了.
So, I should take you home soon.
对不?已经有点晚了.
Right? It's kind of late.
我不知道.
I don't know.
我想去散散步,你想散步吗?
I feel like walking. You feel like walking?
当然.
Sure.
谢谢你请我吃饭.
Thanks for dinner.
-你太客气了.-刚才真的很愉快.
- You're so welcome.
- It was really nice.
这可能是我吃过最贵的一顿了.
It's probably the most expensive meal
I ever had.
我们不得不迁移到密苏里.
We had to relocate to Missouri.
刚赶到那,我就试着加入空军...
Soon as I got there,
I tried to join the Air Force...
...可是他们的招聘人员出去吃午饭了.
...but their recruiter was out to lunch.
陆战队的招聘组看到我在邮局那走就说:
The Marine Corps recruiter sees me
pacing there in the post office and says:
...埃莉诺罗斯福谈起过你...
'"Eleanor Roosevelt was talking about you.'"
埃莉诺罗斯福?
Eleanor Roosevelt?
是啊,于是我说,开什么国际玩笑,她都死了.
Yeah. So I say, '"That's quite a trick,
seeing as she's dead.'"
他说,"这是她死前说的.
He says, '"She said it before she died.
她称你为一个性欲过剩,训练过度,营养不良,工资过少的杀人机器.
'"She called you an oversexed, overtrained,
underfed, underpaid killing machine.'"
我还以为他疯了,于是我就问他,我说:
I thought he was crazy.
So I asked him, I said:
你他妈在说什么东西?
'"What the hell are you talking about? '"
他说:她当时在讲的是陆战队员.
He says, '"She was talking about Marines.
...而对我来说你看起来就像个陆战队员.
'"And you sure as hell
look like a Marine to me.'"
我觉得那还是挺利落的.
I thought that was pretty neat.
于是我狂奔回家,找到老爸,带他回来...
So I bolted home, got the old man,
brought him back...
...然后他飞一般的签下那些文书,差点扭了他的手腕.
...and he signed those papers so damn fast
he nearly sprained his wrist.
我那时还是个小混蛋,不过我只有16岁.
I was a little shit back then,
but I was only 16.
我不觉得你是个小混蛋.
I don't think you're a little shit.
哎呀,谢谢.
Gee, thanks.
-好咯.-美极了.
- There you go.
- It's a beauty.
太他妈棒了.
Out-fucking-standing.
真的,太他妈棒了!
I mean, out-fucking-standing!
起来，下一个我来，
Get up. Me next.
好，记住了...
Okay, and remember...
...在完全一样的地方给他纹个完全一样的蜜蜂.
...exact same bee
on the exact same spot for him.
知道了.
Gotcha.
还有,急着呆会还有个叫博雷斯的来.
And remember, there's another one
of us coming. Birdlace.
他现在还没到,不过也给他纹一样的.
He ain't here yet,
but exact same thing for him.
一样的地方,一样的蜜蜂.
Same spot and same bee.
行,行.
Yeah. Yeah.
因为我们有四个人.
'Cause there's four of us.
四蜂团队.
Four Bees.
博雷斯,贝尔津.
There's Birdlace and Berzin.
我叫比尔.
My name's Buell.
该死的,奥基!少烦他，看在上帝的份上。
Goddamn it, Okie! Leave the fucking guy
alone, for Christ's sakes.
他是本杰明。
He's Benjamin.
埃迪，我还会再见到你吗？
Eddie, will I get to see you some more?
我不知道，你想吗？
I don't know. You want to?
想。
Yeah.
好啊，等我回来我就来带你出去玩。
Okay, then I'll take you out
as soon as I get back.
从哪回来？
Get back from where?
我明天一早就要出海。
Well, I'm shipping out
first thing tomorrow morning.
出国去。
Going overseas.
-去哪？-冲绳岛。
- Where are you going?
- Okinawa.
不过我瞄准的是另一个地方。
But I'm aiming for this other place.
印度边上的一个小国家，叫越南。
It's a little country near India
called Vietnam.
我读到过这个。
I read about it.
-他们那边是不是在打仗？-不，不是。
- Aren't they fighting there or something?
- No, not really.
我们去那边只是作为顾问什么的，教他们如何应付党员。
We'll just be there as advisers
to teach them how to handle the Commies.
那很危险的啊。
That could be dangerous.
不会。
No.
打打小仗而已。
Kick a little ass, take a few names.
几个月后就能回来。
Be back in a couple of months.
你之前怎么不告诉我你明天要离开。
Why didn't you tell me before
that you were leaving?
我认为这听起来像胡扯。
I thought it would sound like bullshit.
你懂的，那种为了跟你上床才说的。
You know, something just to say
to get into your skivvies.
-你介意我写信给你吗？-给我？当然不介意了，那简直太好了。
- Would you mind if I wrote you?
- Me? Hell, no. That would be great.
想去北滩那家叫寂静人生咖啡的俱乐部吗？
Want to go to this club in North Beach
called the Still Life Cafe?
我想有天能去那唱歌。
I want to sing there one day.
等我给你写信，你会明白的。
When I write about it, you'll understand.
好啊，行。
Yeah. Sure.
我们也不一定非要去，我只是觉得会不错，但是如果你现在要回去，没事的。
We don't have to. I thought it'd be nice,
but if you have to get back, that's okay.
在我明早归队前都没事。
As long as I'm back for formation
in the morning, it's fine.
好。
Okay.
-你也要给我写信啊。-我会的。
- You got to write me, too.
- I will.
你看起来不太像那种写信的类型。
You don't seem much
like the letter-writing kind.
-你没事吧？-我很好。
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
只是不太喜欢血。
I just don't like blood.
对不起，这是控制不来的。
Sorry. I can't help it.
你确定你没事？
You sure you're okay?
我很好。
I'm fine.
你马上就能纹好了是吗？
You'll be done soon, right?
很快，看起来多好啊。
Real soon. Looking nice.
我不敢相信我们终于纹了。
I can't believe we finally did it.
我们已经说说要纹这些蜜蜂说了两个月了。
We talked about getting these bees
for two months.
好咯。蜜蜂，这是我的蜜蜂。
There you go. It's a bee. It's my bee.
我的蜜蜂在笑诶。
My bee is smiling.
贝尔津，你的蜜蜂脸上有笑容吗？
Berzin, your bee have a smile on his face?
这个有个巨大的笑脸，我不觉得像我诶。
This one has a huge grin.
I don't think that's me.
看见板上那对胸没？
You see the tits on this broad?
很赞。
Nice pair.
我的这个也一样的吧？
This gonna look the same?
完全一样的蜜蜂？完全一样的位置？
Exact same bee? Exact same spot?
有跟长这样的胸的人交往过吗？
Ever been with somebody
with tits like that?
-当然了，你呢？-废话。
- Sure. Haven't you?
- Yeah, sure.
-真的？-是的.
- Really?
- Yes.
好吧。
Okay.
-奥基，你怎么样了？-没出汗哦。
- Okie, how you doing?
- No sweat.
他妈的博雷斯去哪了？该轮到他了。
Where's fucking Birdlace? It's his turn.
我告诉你们，要是博雷斯不来，我就替他纹了。
I tell you what. If Birdlace
doesn't show up, I'll get his for him.
这么说，吉姆斯恩不存在咯。
So Jim Swaine doesn't exist.
你也不知道谁是伍迪加斯里或者皮特西哲。
And you don't know
who Woody Guthrie is or Pete Seeger.
我所知道的民族歌手只有彼得，鲍尔，和玛丽。
The only folk singers I know
is Peter, Paul and Mary.
-他们在这呢。-很搞笑。
- There they are now.
- Very funny.
彼得，鲍尔和玛丽不是真实的民族歌手。
Peter, Paul and Mary
are not real folk singers.
-不是？-不是。
- No?
- No.
真正的民族歌手会自己写歌。
Real folk singers write their own stuff.
他们讲述他们的内心想法。
They say what's on their minds.
-他们是很了不起的。-怎么说？
- They can make things happen.
- How's that?
他们的音乐能改变世界。
Their music can change the world.
要是你想改变世界...
If you want to change the world...
...你干嘛不加入陆战队然后开始射击？
...why don't you join the Marines
and start shooting?
射击能很快改变事物。
Shooting changes things real quick.
我无法相信你居然这么说。
I can't believe you just said that.
-呃，我就是说了。-太可笑了。
- Well, I just did.
- That's ridiculous.
开枪解决不了任何事情。
Shooting doesn't solve anything.
你朝别人开枪，人家也打回来。
You shoot at people,
people shoot back at you.
当你对着别人唱歌的时候，你要传达的信息直接就能进入灵魂。
When you sing to people,
your message goes straight to the soul.
你打开一个新的观点，且给予缓和。
You open a new point of view.
You disarm them.
我只知道肯尼迪总统派遣军队去做出改变...
All I know is that President Kennedy's
sending troops to make some changes...
....而且他绝对没有给他们发放吉他.
..and he certainly didn't issue them guitars.
有些人用音乐战胜侵略.
There are people who use
music over aggression.
听过那首歌“我们万众一心”吗？
Ever heard the song We Shall Overcome?
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
干嘛...你为什么笑啊?
What... Why are you laughing?
-我没在笑.-你明明在笑.
- I'm not laughing.
- Yes, you are.
你觉得这是笑话?
You think this is some joke?
你根本没听过那首歌.
You've never even heard this song.
瞎说.贝尔津老是在瞎哼这歌.
Bullshit. Berzin goofs on it all the time.
真好笑.
That's funny.
那只能证明你的朋友不止是个骗子...
All that proves
is that your friend is not only a cheat...
...还是个彻底的智障.
...but a complete moron.
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
嘿,萝斯!
Hey, Rose!
你才认识他,你就叫他骗子?
You just met the guy.
You're calling him a cheat?
他就是个骗子.玛西不是他找来的,是他雇来的.
He is a cheat. He didn't find Marcie.
He hired her.
-他甚至叫她不要戴她的假牙.-噢,不是吧.
- He even told her not to wear her teeth.
- oh,Come on.
他就是这么干的.我偷听到他们为此事争执.
He did. I overheard them fighting about it.
他想把她的那笔分红给赖掉.
He was trying to chisel her out of her share.
他不止是个骗子和智障,还是个吝啬鬼.
He's not only a cheat and a moron,
he's a cheapskate.
那个狗日的.
That son of a bitch.
嘿!等下.
Hey! Hold it.
怎么回事啊?
What's going on here?
我可不会把在美国的最后几个小时花费在跟你争执上.
I ain't spending my last few hours stateside
arguing with you.
特别是你.我喜欢你.
Especially you. I like you.
该死的.
Damn it.
我很抱歉要是...
I'm sorry if...
我很抱歉要是我让你不开心了或怎么着.
I'm sorry if I upset you in any way.
那首歌对我来说很重要,我不想看到它被那样取笑.
That song is very important to me.
I don't like to see it ridiculed like that.
我明白了,对不起.
I understand that. I'm sorry.
我也对不起.
I'm sorry.
我对不起.
不.是我对不起,所以你闭嘴.
No. I'm sorry, so shut up.
谢谢,可是我是真的对不起,所以你闭嘴.
Thank you, but I'm really sorry,
so you shut up.
行,只要一句话,我们会在那的.
Yeah. Just give us the word,
and we're there.
-就你们俩?-就我们俩.
- Just the two of you?
- Just the two of us.
她唱歌,我弹奏,然后...
She sings, I play, and...
嘿,鲍勃.
Hey, Bob.
-我带他来转转,行不?-行.
- I'm just going to show him around, okay?
- Sure.
你之前在哪表演过?
Where did you play?
几星期前我们在鲁迪的地方表演过,他们很欣赏我们.
We played over at Rudy's
a couple weeks ago. They really dug us.
就是这里.
So this is it.
你们有经纪人吗?
You guys have a manager?
没有.
No.
-挺有意思的,蛮好的.-是啊.
- Well, it's interesting. It's nice.
- Yeah.
-你在这唱过歌吗?-没有.
- You ever sing here?
- No.
我想等我头发长一点,而且我要自己创作.
I'm waiting for my hair to get longer
and write my own stuff.
然后再准备胡特.
Then I'll be ready to hoot.
胡特?什么东西?
Hoot? What's that?
跟胡滕南妮有点像.
Short for hootenanny.
每个星期四晚上,每个人都能上台来唱歌...
Every Tuesday night,
anybody can come up on stage and sing...
...然后要是鲍勃喜欢的话,他就可能会把他们叫回来...
...and if Bob likes them,
he might ask them back...
...给他们一次演出机会什么的.
...or give them a gig or something.
-你为什么不唱点什么?-什么?
- Why don't you sing something?
- What?
唱点什么,比如...
Yeah. Sing something, like...
比如你在咖啡馆唱的那首.
Like that song you sang earlier at the cafe.
我对那首歌也不太熟悉.
I don't know that song very well.
没事,我就想看你在上面唱.
That's okay.
I just want to see you up there.
呃...
Well...
你有舞台,还有我,作为观众.
You've got the stage.
You've got me as the audience.
所以干嘛不唱呢？
So why don't you just sing?
求你了？
Please?
好吧。
Okay.
我不太会弹钢琴。
I don't know piano all that well.
没关系。
That's okay.
我就简单弹弹好了。
I'll just play it very simply.
可以。
That's fine.
好吧。
Okay.
萝斯，紧紧盯住他们的蠢脑瓜子，然后猛击！
Rose, lock your eyes on their numskulls
and brain them!
耶！
Yeah!
看着，我想你会喜欢这个的。
See, I think that you're going to like this.
广告商发现美国的女性...
Advertisers have found
that the women of America...
...对她们使用的香皂品种具有相当大的兴趣.
...are keenly interested
in the type of soap they use.
实际上,美国的男性也对产品具有很大的性趣...
In fact, the men of America
have a keen interest in the product...
...以及这产品是如何被使用的.
...and how it is used also.
外置马达在这个国家...
The outboard motor has brought a
renewed interest...
...为了水上运动带来了新的兴趣.
...in water sports in this country.
伟大的解放啊,不是吗?
Outstanding liberty, isn't it?
太他娘伟大了.
Out-fucking-standing.
...提供练习的湖泊与河流...
...lakes and streams for exercise...
我想我该走了.你明天还要早起.
I guess I should go.
You got to get up early in the morning.
是啊,你也是.
Yeah. You, too.
恩.
Yeah.
那么我现在就离开咯.
So I'll just leave now.
或者,你可以...
Or, you could...
...进来坐一会.
...come in for a minute.
你这么想的吗?
You think so?
是啊,坐一会,要是你想的话.
Yeah, for a little while, if you want.
我很乐意.
I'd love to.
好吧,走吧.
Okay, let's go.
恩.
Okay.
她在睡觉吗?
s she sleeping?
对,她向来都开着电视睡的.
Yeah. She always sleeps with the TV on.
你想听点音乐吗?
Do you want to hear some music?
好啊.
Sure.
这些人都是谁?
Who are these people?
噢,这是马尔维娜雷诺兹.
Okay. This is Malvina Reynolds.
我今天唱的那首歌就是她写的.
She's the one who wrote the song
that I sang today.
还有,还有...
And, and...
那是伍迪加斯林.
That's Woody Guthrie.
那是皮特西哲.
And that's Pete Seeger.
那是琼贝兹.
That's Joan Baez.
她是我最喜欢的一个.
She's my favorite.
还有那个是鲍勃迪伦.
And there's Bob Dylan.
你认识他的对不?
You know him, right?
然后那个是奥黛塔,她有最美的声音.
And that's Odetta.
She has the most beautiful voice.
还有...
And...
不好意思,没有吉姆斯恩的照片.
Sorry, no pictures of Jim Swaine.
你想玩音乐宾果吗?
Do you want to play musical bingo?
-好啊.-好.
- Sure.
- Okay.
这个很好玩的.
It's really fun.
好呀.
Okay.
恩,你可以当大师...
Okay. You can be the maestro...
....然后你拿12片.
..and you get 12 chips.
拿着,你可以数数.
Here. You can count those out.
然后我也拿12片...
And I'll get 12, and...
这跟宾果一样吗?
Is this like bingo?
这是音乐宾果.
It's a musical bingo.
我不会玩宾果.
I can't play bingo.
-不会?-不会.
- No?
- No.
好吧.
Okay.
我们不必玩宾果.
We don't have to play bingo.
不必.
No.
-可以吗?-恩.
- Is this okay?
- Yeah.
行?
Yeah?
要我换衣服吗?
Do you think I should change maybe?
我要换吗?
Should I change?
啊?
Yeah?
好吧,我去换下.
Okay. I'll change.
我的睡裙.
My nightgown.
我就...我进这里面去换.
And I'll just... I'll go in here and change.
你看起来不错.
You look good.
-你看起来很漂亮.-谢谢你.
- You look real good.
- Thank you.
不好意思,这床小了点.
Sorry. The bed's small.
我们可以...吗?
Couldn't we just...
这是我的地址.
Here's my address.
要是你想的话,可以写信给我.
You can write if you want.
照顾好你自己.
Take care of yourself.
好的.
Okay.
再见,埃迪.
Goodbye, Eddie.
再见.
'Bye.
赏点钱买杯咖啡吧?
How about a dime for coffee?
-博雷斯下士报到.-你他妈去哪了?
- Corporal Birdlace reporting for duty.
- Where the hell have you been?
Yeah.
我不知道,我忘记了.
I don't know. I forget.
我看起来比你好多了.
I look a lot better than you.
发生什么事了?
What happened?
我们打了一架.
We had a pisser of a time.
扁了几个乌贼混蛋.
Tangled assholes with some squid.
去了一家纹身店,遇见了个很感性的女人.
Went to a skin flick,
met a very sensitive woman.
她给我们三个口交,每个人收10块钱,然后在那之前,我们弄了个纹身.
She did the three of us for $10.
And before that, we got a tattoo.
-一只蜜蜂.-给你看看.
- A bee.
- Check it out.
蜜蜂代表四蜂团队.你觉得怎样?
A bee for the Four Bees.
What do you think?
挺好的,我喜欢.
I like it, it's nice.
贝尔津代你纹了.
Berzin got yours for you.
给他看看,贝尔津.
Show him, Berz.
死开.
Fuck off.
挺好看的.
That's pretty.
你欠我一只蜜蜂.
You owe me a bee.
请注意,所有的军事人员.
Attention, all military personnel.
去金银岛的班车即将出发...
The shuttle for Treasure Island departs...
走吧.
Let's go.
怎么说?你到底告不告诉我们?
So? You going to tell us or what?
都说出来呗,博雷斯.
Spit it out, Birdlegs.
我跟她说好不会跟任何人讲的.
I told her I wouldn't tell no one.
拜托,你个混蛋,我们跟你讲.
Come on, you asshole. We tell you.
低调点,她结婚了的.
Keep it down. She was married.
已婚的?她是已婚的?你个王八蛋!她已婚诶.
Married? She was married?
You fuck! She was married.
太棒了,下士.太他妈棒了.
Outstanding, Corporal.
Out-fucking-standing.
你知道他们怎么说吗,结了婚的是最好的.
You know what they say. Married's best.
她们不说出去,她们不怀孕.
'"They don't tell, they don't swell.'"
长得好看吗?
Good-looking?
噢,那是,32岁,金发,身材那是...
Oh, yeah. 32, blond, built like a...
32岁?搞什么?爱操老奶奶?
32? What are you, some grandma-fucker?
要是这个老奶奶长成这样.你拿你屁股赌吧.
If the grandmother looked like this,
you bet your ass.
她长得真的很美.
She was real good-looking.
她无法满足.
She couldn't get enough.
她老公不咋关注她,估计是个同志.
Her old man didn't give her attention.
Probably a fag.
然后你觉得作为一个少校会怎样做?
What do you expect
from a lieutenant commander in personnel?
一个军官的老婆!太他妈帕!
An officer's wife!
That's out-fucking-standing!
你知道么,贝尔津?我觉得你跟我满嘴的胡扯.
You know what, Berzin?
I think you and me are full of shit.
拜托,博雷斯,你什么意思?
Come on, Birdlace. What's your beef?
那个缺牙的烂货,你带去派对的那个...
That toothless sack of shit
that you took to the party...
在斗狗赛里.
The dogfight.
那是事先安排好的对不?
That was a setup, right?
你怎么这么想？
What makes you think that?
我昨晚也没和军官的老婆在一起。
I wasn't out with the officer's wife
last night.
我和萝斯在一起。是她告诉我的。
I was out with Rose. She told me.
我就知道她会告诉你。
I figured she was going to do that.
昨晚我们在唐人街纹身的时候我看到你跟她在一块。
I saw you with her last night in Chinatown
while we were getting our bees put on.
你在开玩笑吧。
You're shitting me.
-好极了。-我不会告诉他们的。
- Fucking A.
- I won't tell them.
你也不会告诉他们我在比赛中作弊是不？
Just like you won't tell them
I fixed the fight, right?
我们怎么会变得那么能扯淡？
How did we get to be so full of shit?
我是说，我们怎么变成狗日的白痴了？
I mean, how did we become
these fucking idiots?
我当时坐在这思考，然后...管他呢。
I was sitting here thinking about it, and...
Fuck it.
我想我也不知道这些是怎么开始的.
I guess I don't know what started it all.
-是啊,别管了.-恩.
- Yeah. Forget about it.
- Right.
-睡觉吧.-恩.
- Go back to sleep.
- Right.
不值得.
It ain't worth it.
所以你是公平的赢得了斗狗赛...
So you won the dogfight fair and square...
...而我昨晚和长官的老婆在一起.
...and I was dating the officer's wife
for one night.
-收到了,下士.-真是狗屎.
- Roger that, Corporal.
- Bullshit.
知道我什么意思了吗?
See what I mean?
知道.
I do.
我给你讲讲什么事胡扯.
Let me tell you something about bullshit.
到处都在胡扯.
It's everywhere.
你对我胡扯,我信.
You hit me with a little, I buy it.
我对你胡扯,你信.
I hit you with a little, you buy it.
这不代表我们是傻逼.
It doesn't make us idiots.
那代表我们是好兄弟.
That's what makes us buddies.
我们信部队跟我们讲的,那使我们成为陆战队员.
We buy what the Corps hands out,
and that's what makes us Marines.
然后部队听肯尼迪胡扯...
And the Corps is buying the bullshit
from Kennedy...
...肯尼迪又听每个美国人胡扯.
...and Kennedy's buying the bullshit
from everybody in the US of fuckin' A.
那代表我们是美国人.
And that's what makes us Americans.
-但还终归到底还是胡扯.-正确.
- It's still bullshit.
- Right.
而我们就身处在我们嘴巴上说出来的胡扯中,老兄.
And we're in it
up to our goddamn lips, buddy.
懂我在说什么吗?
See what I'm saying?
贝尔津,你还是挺能从万事中找出点道理来的.
Berzin, you can make sense out of anything.
我不知道我说的有没有意义,不过...
I don't know if I'm making sense, but...
对我来说有很多意义,老兄.
This makes a hell of a lot of sense
to me, boy.
关于这点不是胡扯.
There's no bullshit in this.
上帝啊.
Jesus.
真他娘的"迷人",奥基.相当他娘的"迷人".
Very fucking charming, Okie.
Very fucking charming.
我刚才闻到的是俄克拉荷马香气吗?
Was that the Okie aroma I smell?
嘿,屎鸟,再跟我说一遍,她是不是很火辣?
Hey, Birdshit, tell me again,
was she a fox or what?
-啥?-那个,军官的老婆.
- What?
- You know, the officer's wife.
她有多美?
How good-looking was she?
-告诉我.-好吧,告诉他.
- Tell me.
- All right. Tell him.
我告诉你,你个可悲的狗日的.
I'll tell you this, you sorry son of a bitch.
她美到你愿意爬过地雷区...
She was so fine,
you'd crawl through a minefield...
...只为了闻闻拖着她内裤的洗衣车的轮胎.
...just to smell the tires on the laundry
truck hauling away her skivvies.
不了个是吧!
Get out of here!
滚开!
Get off of me!
嘿,拜托.
Hey, come on!
别弄到我的头发.
Watch my hair!
-戴利.-到.
- Daley.
- Here.
-埃利希.-到.
- Erlich.
- Here.
-贝利.-到.
- Bailey.
- Here.
-莱克.-到.
- Riker.
- Here.
-林肯.-到.
- Lincoln.
- Here.
-桑德斯.-到.
- Sanders.
- Here.
-萨诺夫.-到.
- Sarnof.
- Here.
-泰特.-到.
- Tate.
- Here.
NBC新闻的鲍勃麦克尼尔在线上为我们报告,请继续,鲍勃.
We have NBC's Bob MacNeil on the line
now with a report. Please go ahead, Bob.
白宫的新闻秘书马尔科姆吉尔达...
White House Press Secretary
Malcolm Kilduff...
...刚刚宣布肯尼迪总统...
...has just announced
that President Kennedy...
...在中环标准时间约一点时去世,大概35分钟前.
...died at approximately 1:00 Central
Standard Time, just about 35 minutes ago.
-在被一个不知名的暗杀者...
...- After being shot at...
- After being shot...
...枪击...
...by an unknown assailant...
...在一辆开往达拉斯的车队行驶中.
...during a motorcade ride
through downtown Dallas.
...在一辆开往达拉斯的车队行驶中.
...during a motorcade ride
through downtown Dallas.
-总理在约25分钟前...
- The president died...
...死去.
...approximately 25 minutes...
我给你张4...
I'll see your four...
...然后给你张5.
...and raise you five.
你们想听个笑话吗?
Y'all want to hear a joke?
我赢了.
That's it. I won.
搞什么飞机?
What's this shit?
-想听个笑话吗?-你想扯什么?
- Want to hear a joke?
- What are you trying to pull?
-你以为我是白痴吗?-赶紧讲那个他妈的笑话.
- You think I'm stupid.
- Tell the fucking joke.
知道一个鬼对蜜蜂说什么吗?
What did the ghost say to the bee?
我不知道.
I don't know.
噗,比,噗,比.
'"Boo, bee. Boo, bee.'"
说实话,这笑话很赞.
Actually, that's pretty good.
那真的很好笑,奥基.
That's real funny, Okie.
我的膝盖!
My knee!
我中枪了。
I've been hit.
-我需要帮助！-他妈的我的手臂！
- I need help!
- My fucking arm!
本杰明！
Benjamin!
他死了！他死了！那个狗日的死了！
He's dead! He's dead!
The motherfucker's dead!
本杰明在哪？
Where's Benjamin?
埃迪，你给我她妈的坚持住！
Eddie, don't you fucking give up on me!
旧金山。
San Francisco.
下车时候注意脚下。
Watch your step getting off.
谢谢你们的到来，朋友们。
So, thanks for coming, folks.
嘿，兄弟，你杀了多少人？
Hey, man, how many babies did you kill?
我们在控股公司有大哥。
We're having Big Brother
and the Holding Company.
对海特社区义诊有好处。
A benefit
for the Haight Community free clinic.
趁涨价前去看看吧。
Check it out before the prices go up.
他背上有只蝎子。
He had a scorpion on his back.
一个纹身，有这么大。
A tattoo, like this big.
就像那些无袖T恤。
It was one of those T-shirts with no sleeves.
你好吗？
How are you doing?
给我来个CC和一杯水。Let me have a CC and water.
-卡尔也想要来一个。-好的。
- Yeah, I think Karl wants one, too.
- Right.
-我付不起一个，给我一拔。-行。
- I can't afford one. Give me a raise.
- Yeah.
当兵的第一个。
Runner on at first.
一共一美元十美分。
That'll be $1.10.
给你两块，不用找了。
Here's $2. Keep the change.
谢谢。
Thanks.
-那个很不错嘛，能干什么么？-什么？
- That's nice. It do anything?
- What?
那个知更鸟。
The bluebirds.
它没带我我该去的地方，可它还在飞翔。
It didn't take me where it was supposed to,
but it still flies.
我们刚才就在谈论纹身呢。
We were just talking about tattoos.
这蜜蜂不错。
Nice bees.
你才刚纹的？
You just get them?
-恩。-好吧。
- Yeah.
我有一个会跳舞的。
I got one that dances.
那男的不想看你的肚子,卡尔.
The man doesn't want
to see your belly.Karl.
我只说了我有个会跳舞的纹身.
All I said was I got one that dances.
相信我,没什么了不起的.
Believe me, it's no big deal.
给我看看.
Let me see it.
老天啊.
For crying out loud.
你看懂没?肚皮舞者哦?
You get it? Belly dancer?
嘿,我是在TJ地方纹的.
Hey, I got it in TJ.
你去过TJ地方吗?
You ever been to TJ?
去过.
Yeah.
我这个是从新兵训练营出来后在Dego地方弄的.
I got this one in Dego
after I got out of boot camp.
你是个陆战队员?
You a Marine?
是的,先生,
Yes, sir.
-在越南?-是.
- Vietnam?
- Yeah.
好吧,够糟的.
Yeah. Bummer.
那个不要收费了吧,卡尔.
No charge on that, Karl.
-谢谢.-谢谢你.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
孩子,这儿发生了很大的变化.
Boy, things have really changed
around here.
是啊，你可以再说一遍。
Yeah. You can say that again.
你没在开玩笑。
You ain't kidding.
萝斯还在经营对街那家店吗？那间咖啡馆。
Rose still run that place
across the street, the cafe?
有好几个叫萝斯的呢。
There's been a couple of Roses.
是啊，不过我想现在应该已经传到她们的外孙女手里了吧。
Yeah, but I think they're grooming
a granddaughter of hers now.
我想我之前见过那个外孙女。她有点胖胖的对不？
I think I've seen the granddaughter before.
She's kind of chubby?
胖胖的？她那哪叫胖。
Chubby? She ain't no prize.
好像你才是赢家似地，卡尔？
Like you're some kind of winner, Karl?
我是个爱人。
I am a lover.
爱人？
A lover?
萝斯？
Rose?
嗨。
Hi.